RESUME ----

MY RESUME

Profile

JOSE FRANCO OLEA VALLEJO

I'm a professional with work experience in software development (Front-End and Back-End), Microsoft Azure cloud services administration and implementation of architecture designs in the cloud to provide solutions to new and current needs, I also have Azure DevOps management experience creating and managing projects and pipelines for continuous integration (CI) and continuous deployment (CD) both in Azure and On-Premise infrastructure.

- | +52 55 2084 6860
- 📧 franco8802@gmail.com

Languages

SPANISH

Native

ENGLISH

Advanced

Education

BACHELOR OF "MATEMÁTICAS APLICADAS Y COMPUTACIÓN" (GRADUATED ONLY)

Aug 2012 - Nov 2016

FES Acatlán, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México

Groups & activities:

- Algorithmics and Competitive Programming Group
- Videogames Development Group

Awards & leadership:

- 27th Place in ACM ICPC Mexico Occident & Pacific Programming Contest, coordinated by ITESO University, 2013
- Honorable Mention in ACM ICPC Mexico Occident & Pacific Programming Contest, coordinated by ITESO University, 2013
- Honorable Mention in ACM ICPC Mexico & Central America Contest, SEDE ESCOM IPN, 2013
- Honorable Mention in ACM ICPC Mexico & Central America Programming
 Contest SEDE ITSM Querétaro 2013
- Contest, SEDE ITSM Querétaro, 2013
 Honorable Mention in ACM ICPC Finals in Mexico CitiesProgramming
- Contest, coordinated by ITESO University, 2013
 Honorable Mention in ACM ICPC JaliscoProgramming Contest, coordinated
- by ITESO University, 2013
 Recognition by the Government of the State of Mexico for being an Excellence Student and having the best grade in my class, 2012
- Constancy by Academia Mexicana de Lógica, A.C. & Universidad Autónoma de Nayarit for having competed in the final stage of the IX InternationalOlympiad in Logic, 2012

Certifications

 MICROSOFT CERTIFICATION EXAM: AZ-300 MICROSOFT AZURE ARCHITECT TECHNOLOGIES



MICROSOFT TECHNOLOGY ASSOCIATE: CLOUD FUNDAMENTALS CERTIFICATION

2017

Microsoft

 MICROSOFT TECHNOLOGY ASSOCIATE: SECURITY FUNDAMENTALS CERTIFICATION

2017

Microsoft

 MICROSOFT TECHNOLOGY ASSOCIATE: DATABASE FUNDAMENTALS CERTIFICATION

2017

Microsoft

 MICROSOFT TECHNOLOGY ASSOCIATE: HTML5 APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT FUNDAMENTALS CERTIFICATION

2017

Microsoft

 MICROSOFT TECHNOLOGY ASSOCIATE: SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT FUNDAMENTALS CERTIFICATION

2017

Microsoft

 DIPLOMAED IN VIDEOGAMES DEVELOPMENT AND INTERACTIVE & 3D MULTIMEDIA APPLICATION

Dec 2015 - May 2016

Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México

ORACLE CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL: JAVA SE 6 PROGRAMMER

2013

Oracle

Professional Experience

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

May 2018 - Present

Comisión Reguladora de Energía

- Tech Lead in the design, development, and maintenance of web services and systems
- Lead development teams for differente projects and requirements.
- Lead the design and architecture of new systems.
- Develop and lead new systems requirments and bug fixes.
- Creation of NuGet packages for custom and generic functions, classes and interfaces.
- Azure administrator
- Implementation of a new architecture for the Azure infrastructure of the institution with geo-redundancy and communication with On-Premise
- Creation and management of laaS, PaaS, communication, data and analytics services.
- Cost & budget management and projection based on current and future needs and requirements.
- Infrastructure monitoring with azure alerts and dashboards.
- Azure DevOps administrator
- Managing and implementing Git Branching strategies and policies,
 Continuous Integration & Continuous Delivery pipelines.
- Managing and installing agent pools and deployment pools on Azure and On-Prem Windows servers for Azure Pipelines.
- Migrating TFVC Repositories to Git
- Planning and tracking activities for projects creating sprints and using boards, creating custom Scrum processes according to the needs.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ASSISTANT MANAGER

Dec 2016 - Apr 2018

Comisión Reguladora de Energía

- Manage Azure DevOps repositories and prjects
- Development and maintenance of web systems and REST APIs with .Net Framework 4.5+ and jQuery
- Technical problems resolution
- Continuous improvements of web systems
- jQuery plugins creation
- Plugins creation and code refactoring to improve code performance and quality

• WEB DEVELOPER

Dec 2015 - Nov 2016

Lagash

- Development and maintenance of web systems and REST APIs with .Net Framework 4.5+ and jQuery
- Technical problems resolution
- Continuous improvements of web systems
- jQuery plugins creation
- Plugins creation and code refactoring to improve code performance and quality